Say hola to his little friends.
Puss in Boots: The Last Wish is a animation, adventure,
fantasy film directed by Joel Crawford.
Puss in Boots discovers that his passion for adventure has taken its toll: He has burned
through eight of his nine lives, leaving him with only one life left.
Puss sets out on an epic journey to find the mythical
Last Wish and restore his nine lives.
Puss in Boots (voice), played by Antonio Banderas.
Kitty Softpaws (voice), played by Salma Hayek Pinault.
Perrito (voice), played by Harvey Guillén.
Wolf (voice), played by Wagner Moura.
Goldilocks (voice), played by Florence Pugh.
Mama Bear (voice), played by Olivia Colman.
Puss in Boots: The Last Wish is a 2022 American animated adventure comedy film
directed by Joel Crawford and written by Paul Fisher and Tommy Swerdlow.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation, it is the sequel to Puss in
Boots (2011) and the sixth in the Shrek film series.
As with its predecessor, the film is based on the character
introduced in Shrek 2 (2004) and inspired by the fairy tale.
Antonio Banderas and Salma Hayek reprise their respective roles as the titular character and Kitty Softpaws, with Harvey Guillén, Florence Pugh,
Olivia Colman, Ray Winstone, Samson Kayo, John Mulaney, Wagner Moura, Da'Vine Joy Randolph, and Anthony Mendez joining the cast.
Set after the events of Shrek Forever After (2010), the story follows Puss in Boots, who teams up with Kitty
Softpaws and Perrito to find the Last Wish of the fallen Wishing Star to restore eight of his nine lives.
They race against other fairy tale characters seeking the same
treasure, while a sinister wolf hunts Puss himself.
Planning for a sequel to Puss in Boots began in November 2012, but it
languished in development hell until it was revived in November 2018.
In February 2019, it was announced that the film would be helmed by Bob Persichetti, head of
story of the first film and co-director of Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse (2018).
By March 2021, Crawford had replaced Persichetti as director.
The story draws inspiration from Spaghetti Western films, with The Good,
the Bad and the Ugly (1966) cited as a particular influence.
The film's style was inspired by Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse.
With new technology, the team was able to give the film a painterly style to resemble a fairy-tale
story, diverging from the visual style of previous installments in the Shrek franchise.
Puss in Boots: The Last Wish premiered at Lincoln Center in New York City on November 25, 2022, and
was theatrically released in the United States on December 21, by Universal Pictures.
It received acclaim from critics, and was a commercial success, grossing $484 million on a
production budget of $90–110 million, becoming the tenth-highest-grossing film of 2022.
It was nominated for Best Animated Feature at the Academy Awards, the Golden
Globes, the Critics' Choice Awards, and the British Academy Film Awards.
The film explores themes of fairy tale, sequel,
talking dog, spin off, aftercreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.